只有我
it's just me
和
and
你，只有我
you it's just me
大家好
hello everyone
无论你在哪里，无论什么时候
wherever you are and whatever time
都欢迎你参加我的演讲
it is for you welcome to my talk
关于塞浦路斯组件测试的演讲
on cyprus component testing for v
我的名字叫Jessica Sax，是一家名为Pathai的医疗技术创业公司的工程师。
my name is jessica sax i am a staff engineer
在一家名为Pathai的医疗技术创业公司担任工程师
at a med tech startup called pathai
我来自美国的波士顿
i'm from boston in america
我最近离开了塞浦路斯
and i recently left cyprus
但我仍然作为塞浦路斯的大使参与其中。
but i'm still involved as a cyprus ambassador
我在塞浦路斯工作了两年半。
i worked at cyprus for two and a half years
于2020年3月加入
joining in march 2020
领导团队
led the team that
我在Cyprus工作了两年半，于2020年3月加入，带领团队设计、建造和运送Cyprus组件，在Cyprus进行测试。
designed built and shipped cyprus component testing in cyprus
十、我是Faker JST的成员
ten i'm a faker jst member
偶尔为view和vteco系统做贡献
and the occasional contributor to the view and vteco system
我松散地参与了v测试的开发工作
i'm loosely involved with the development of v test
的开发，也是一个偶尔的贡献者
as an occasional contributor as well
这个
酷
cool
现在，什么是Cypress组件测试？
now what is cypress component testing
Cypress
cypress
组件测试提供了一个可测试的组件工作平台
component testing provides a testable component workbench
为您快速构建和测试
for you to quickly build and test
任何组件，无论其多么简单或复杂
any component no matter how simple or complex
cypress是一个基于浏览器的测试运行器，从cypress 10开始
cypress is a browser based test runner and as of cypress 10
你现在有能力完全测试驱动
you now have the ability to fully test drive
一个单独组件的逻辑
an individual component's logic
包括它的css
including its css
我将告诉你什么
i'll show you what
我的意思是
i mean
实践一个可测试的组件驱动的开发工作流程
practicing a testable component driven development workflow
使你能够将你的工作分解成更容易管理的小块
enables you to break down your work into more manageable chunks
最终导致
ultimately resulting in
组件的开发更有条理
components that are developed more mindfully
这就是Cypress组件测试的样子，比如invudify
this is what cypress component testing looks in like invudify
这相当于视图中的材料UI
which is the view equivalent of material ui
在这个测试中，Cypress正在测试基于canvas的beautifies
in this test cypress is testing out beautifies canvas based
v 颜色选择器组件
v color picker component
在左边，我们有一个命令日志
on the left we have the command log
它显示了所有在这个测试中被执行的命令。
which shows all the commands that have been executed in
这个测试中的所有命令，它们大致上相当于
this test they're roughly equivalent to
你知道每个命令有一行代码
you know one line of code per command
然后在右边你有
and then on the right you have
称为被测程序
what would be called the application under test
如果你是端对端测试
if you were end to end testing
而被称为被测试的组件
instead is called the component under test
这就是我们美丽的颜色选择器
which is our beautiful color picker
我喜欢展示而不是讲述
and i like to show instead of tell
我这次演讲的目的是让你们感受一下
and my goal in this talk is to give you a feel
感受一下我们的开发工作
for weds like to develop
使用 cybers 组件测试
using cybers component testing
因此，为了做到这一点
so to do this
我们将测试一个简单的计数器组件，它有一个最小的
we will be test driving a simple counter component with a min
最大和初始值
max and initial value
我还将展示一下
i will also show off how flexible
我还将展示塞浦路斯组件测试是多么灵活，当它涉及到摄入你的
cyprus component testing is when it comes to ingesting your
兽医配置
vet config
我们正在谈论markdown文件 我们正在谈论spelt文件 jsx
we're talking markdown files we're talking spelt files jsx
它可以处理任何你
it handles anything that you
在你的兽医配置中配置的任何东西
have configured in your vet config
所以让我们把它打开
so let's open it up
好的，现在去看代码
okay heading over to the codes
所以我们将在视图中工作
so we're gonna be working in view
今天，虽然它实际上并不重要
today though it actually doesn't matter
因为Cyprus会处理任何你配置的
because cyprus will handle anything that you have configured
在你的脚部配置中
in your feet config
所以pnpm cyprus打开dashdash组件
so pnpm cyprus open dashdash component
这个模板是基于
this template is based off of the
v tess
而不是v test v tess
not v test v tess
组件模板，我将使用chrome的第一版哦，第五版
component template i'm going to use chrome version one oh five
我们将在该版本中开始测试Cyprus组件
we're going to start cyprus component testing in that version
而且我们要
and we're going to
看看有哪些组件已经存在了组件测试
look at what components component tests exist already
所以我们有这个计数器组件测试
so we have this counter component test
我们可以打，我们也可以看它
we can hit we can either look at it
所以我们来做这个
so let's do that
看看有哪些测试已经存在
and see what tests already exist
我已经在这里写了一些测试
so i've already written a few tests here
我已经写了一些测试，这些测试
i've written a few tests that
检查出我们
check out that we
有一个递减按钮，我们有一个递增按钮
have a decrement button that we have an increment button
它非常小
it's very small
对你们来说可能很小，所以让我们把它变大吧
probably for you guys so let's make it bigger
让我们把我的脸变小
let's make my face smaller
好的
okay
我们有一个增量和一个减量按钮
that we have an increment and a decrement button
你可以看到，当你点击它们时
and you can see that when you click them
什么也没有发生，所以
nothing happens so
我们可能想写一个测试
we probably want to write a test for that
因为我们是在一个计数器中
because we're in a counter
所以只要你把鼠标放在规格名称上
so whenever you hover over the spec name
你就可以在你的思想中打开它。
in the test runner itself in cyprus you can open it in your ide
如果你没有配置好你的思想库
if you don't have your ide configured
它就会要求你配置它 Cyprus是非常聪明的
it will ask you to configure it cyprus can be very smart
所以我打算做的第一件事是
so the first thing i'm going to do
是我要隐藏文件资源管理器
is i'm going to hide the file explorer
我们要写一个测试，说明
and we're going to write a test that says that
计数器
the counter
递减值，当
decrements the value when
点击减去的按钮
the minus button is clicked
让我们把它叫做减法
let's call it the decrement
按钮，因为我在其他地方都叫它递减
button because i'm calling it decrement everywhere else
所以，不仅减去的
so not only should the decrement
选择器是可见的，而且当我们点击它时
selector be visible but when we click it
我们应该把它称为
and we should let's call it the
我不知道
i don't know
我想确保这个值是递增的。
i want to make sure that the value is incremented right
所以在这里面的任何东西
so anything inside of this
data test id counter
所以我们要得到计数器的选择器
so we're gonna get the counter selector
让我们快速实现它
let's implement that really quick
我想把我的屏幕分割开来，我喜欢同时运行我的测试。
i'm gonna split my screen i like to have oh i like
让我的测试和我的开发同时进行
to have my tests running at the same time
和我的开发工作同时进行
as my development
所以我将会
so i'm gonna
得到计数器选择器，你可以看到箭头堆积在一起
get the counter selector you can watch the arrows pile up
我想只使用 "哪个是 "来隔离
and i want to isolate using only which is
这是个
which is a
的方法在许多测试运行器上
method on it in many test runners
包括塞浦路斯
including cyprus
我们要说的是计数器选择器，你可以看到小麦。
we're going to say counter selector you can see the wheat
插件的错误，这是相当酷的一种管道了
plug in errors which is pretty cool kind of pipe up
以及重新运行的速度，所以现在
and how fast that rerun is so now
我们有了计数器选择器，我们可以看到cyprus告诉我们
we have the counter selector and we can see cyprus telling us
嘿，这是整个节点的情况
hey it's the entire node here
我们要点击它
and we're going to click it
对不起，不，我们要去
sorry no we're going to
应该有文字
should have text
它应该是增量加一，所以对不起，初始
it should be increment plus one so sorry initial
加一
plus one
完美，所以我们希望这个节点应该有文本
perfect so we're expecting that this node should have text
但这是为了
but it was for
我们实际上希望包含文本
we actually wanted to contain text
你看那个多余的空格
you see that extra space there
我们不希望有这个额外的空间
we don't want to have this extra space
在这一点上，你应该感觉到这是
and at this point you should be feeling like this is
这时你应该感觉到，这就像一个测试的理想。
kind of like the test ide
所以让我们用命令点击进入计数器，实现
so let's command click into the counter and implement
一个增量函数
an increment function
我们是否说过我们要做增量或减量一秒钟？
did we say we're doing increment or decrement one second
测试说的是什么，测试是递减
what does the test say the test is decrement
所以让我们来实现递减功能。
so let's implement the decrement function so const
decrement 我想我在测试中犯了一个错误，但是
decrement i think i made a mistake actually in my test but
所以我们要说值
so we're going to say value
价值
value
也许应该把它命名为minus minus更合适。
probably should have named it better minus minus
让我们把这个计数器命名为
let's name that counter
小麦是热的，正在重新加载
and wheat is hot is reloading
使用一个Cypress小麦插件
using a cypress wheat plugin
测试运行器在这里，然后
the test runner over here and then
我们要确保当你点击减去的按钮时
we want to make sure that when you click the minus button
我可以看到它是减去的按钮
and i can see that it's the minus button
因为我有一个漂亮的花哨的插件
because i have a nice fancy plugin
当你点击减去的按钮时，我们将调用减法。
when you click the minus button we're going to call decrement
很好
nice
酷
cool
文字是三
text was three
所以减法的工作是正确的
so decrement is working correctly
我的测试实际上是错误的
what my test is actually wrong
该测试应该是减一
the test should be minus one
而且很完美，它确实包含了三
and perfect it does contain three
非常好，现在让我们对增量做同样的事情
very nice now let's do the same thing for increment
让我们复制并粘贴这个测试
so let's copy and paste the test
它
it
当点击 "增加 "按钮时，数值会增加。
increments the value when the
递增按钮的时候，它就会增加数值
increment button is click
让我把我的脸移到屏幕上一个未使用的地方。
let me move my face over to an unused part of the screen
非常好，让我们去说，在所有的地方，它都说是递减的
very nice let's go and say everywhere it says decrement
递增选择器
increment selector
包含初始加一
contain initial plus one
哦
oh
我实现了吗？ 没有，我没有复制增量
did i implement it yet no i did not copy increment
计数器值加加
counter value plus plus
在点击增量的时候
at click increment
这看起来不错
and that looks good
我可以用它来玩哦，非常好
and i can play with it oh very nice
哦，我是否可以进入负数，我不确定。
oh should i be able to go into the negatives i'm not sure
我想计数器一般都有一个最小值的概念，可以选择。
i think counters generally have the idea of a min optionally
可能
probably
和一个最大值，所以让我们继续下去，实现这些东西
and a max so let's go ahead and implement those things
所以让我们说
so let's say
在这里的测试中，它不仅应该有一个递减按钮
in the test here not only should it have a decrement button
让我们抓住这些唯一的东西，把它们拿下来
let's grab these onlys and take them off
轰轰轰
boom boom
它
it
应该不能低于最小值
should not be able to go belowthe minimum value
完美
perfect
所以让我们装上初始值
so let's mount initial
让我们把最小值设为负数，让我们把最小值设为零
let's mount min to be negative let's mount min to be zero
并实现它，所以我们要把初始值设为1
and implement that so we're going to set initial to be one
而最小值实际上是
and the min actually
设置初始值为零，让我们做最小的点击次数
set initial to be zero let's do the minimum number of clicks
我们要抓住减法
we're going to grab the decrement
选择器，我们将
selector we're going to
点击
click
就可以了，这样我们就可以正常工作了。
on that so do we have that's working fine okay
所有的测试都通过了，让我们把这个测试分离出来
all the tests are passing still let's isolate this test
我们已经点击了递减选择器
and we've clicked the decrement selector
而我们不应该这样做
and we should not be able to do this
所以当我们得到计数器选择器时，它应该
so when we get the counter selector it should
有
have
所以你想包含文本
so you want to contain text
它应该包含文本
it should contain text
零，它不应该包含文本
zero it should not contain text
负一
negative one
这很有趣
that's funky
酷
cool
好了，现在让我们添加这些门。
all right so now let's add those gates
这些逻辑门在这里，所以我们只想装饰，如果
those logic gates here so we only want to decorate if
props dot min是
props dot min is
是唯一的一个，如果计数器的值大于
the only one i decommit if counter value is greater than
或
or
没有，只是大于props min
no just greater then props min
这样做对吗？
is that correct
为什么会大喊大叫
why is it yelling
不需要，如果在条件之后
unnecessary if after condition
对象可能是未定义的
object is possibly undefined
哼
我认为我的类型脚本语言服务器
i think my type script language servers
不能正常工作
is not working correctly
所以我打算重新加载这个窗口
so i'm going to reload this window
因为我认为这应该是有效的
because i think this should work
是的
yeah
所以现在我们要做的是
so now we're gonna do
哦
oh
因为大于min的感觉不对
because greater than min doesn't feel right to it
所以我们可以添加一些默认值
so we can add some defaults
而不是真正修复空气类型
versus actually fixing the type air
对不起，Men将是0
sorry men is gonna be zero
最大值将会是
max is gonna be
我不知道
i don't know
像一万
like ten
一万两千
thousand two thousand
在条件允许的情况下，对金钱的重视是不必要的。
to value money spines unnecessary after condition
我想V TESS的借贷规则并不喜欢。
i guess the lenting rules that come with v tess do not like
这个
this
完美
perfect
然后，这个的倒数将是反值加
and then the inverse of this is going to be counter value plus
加
plus
非常好
very nice
递增和递减 现在让我们开始做一些奇怪的事情
increment and decrement now let's start to do some weird stuff
让我们添加一些实用类
let's add some utility classes
让我们添加隐藏，这样你就可以看到没有加号按钮了
let's add hidden so you see there's no more plus button
它还在那里
it's there still
让我们进入
andlet's go into
let's go into the
规格文件，让我们像
spec file again and let's like
运行
run
这一个哦
this one oh
不，我们确实有一个减法，那么增法按钮呢？
no we do have a decrement what about the increment button
它已经告诉我们这个元素是不可见的了
well it's already telling usthat the element isn't visible
而且我们所有的增量按钮测试都失败了，因为
and all of our increment button tests are failing because
用户正试图点击它，但
the user is trying to click it but
我使用的隐藏实用程序类是无显示的。
the hidden utility class i was using has display none on it
如果我们修复了这个css
if we fix the css
一切都能通过
everything passes
花了三百七十六毫秒
and it took three hundred and seventy six mill seconds
来运行所有这些测试
to run all of these tests
它没有我们测试的快，也没有我们测试的快。
it's not as fast as we test it is not as fast as we testhowever
但它确实
it does
处理你所有的样式，而且它确实在真实的浏览器中运行。
process all of your styles and it does run in a real browser
这对我来说是完全有意义的
it makes complete sense to me
我认为
that
它没有那么快
it would not be as fast
我不认为在这个世界上，Cyprus会像无头测试运行器一样快。
i don't see a world in which cyprus would ever be as fast
作为一个无头的测试运行器
as a headless test runner
事实上，除了
except for actually
让我们走吧，这是最大的测试的地方。
let's go it's where the maximum test
除了当你想到快照测试的时候
except for when you think of snapshot testing
当我
when i
适应的美化
adapted beautifies
组件测试从刚刚到塞浦路斯的美化是使用
component tests from just to cyprus beautify was using
来匹配写到光盘上的快照
to match snapshot which writes to the disc
而当你把快照写到光盘上时
and when you write your snapshots to disc
它实际上需要
it actually takes
添了cybers组件测试后，速度就提高了。
a bit of time and adding cybers component testing ended up
加快了
speeding up
美化组件测试
beautifies component tests
这让我很震惊
as a whole which was shocking to me
但事实就是如此，所以
but is what happened so
尽管你可能觉得
even though you might feel
你可能会觉得有点奇怪，因为
you might feel a little weird about
让我们看看最大的是一千
let's see max is a thousand
尽管你可能觉得有点奇怪，因为
even though you might feel a little weird about
有慢的测试比可能的
having slower tests than could be possible
我认为
i think that
有所有的开发工具和调试器可用
having all of the development tools having debuggers available
是绝对值得的
is absolutely worth it
而且
and
我所有的开发风格
i do all of my development styles
测试逻辑 我的所有开发都是在这个画布上完成的
tests logic i do all of my development purely on this canvas
以一种孤立的方式
in an isolated fashion
这很好啊
it's pretty cool
特别是当你想到所有的加载器
and especially when you think of all of the loaders
的时候，你就会发现，这里的所有加载器都在进行着。
that are going on under the hood here
所以我们把它带回V
so let's take it back to v
让我们完成这个测试增量选择器
let's finish this test increment selector
糟糕
whoops
增量选择器
increment selector
包含文本
contain text
让我们看看初始值和最大值
let's see initial and max
应该包含文本一千 让我们回到Cypress这里
should contain text one thousand let's go back to cypress here
用一千零一个
with one thousand and one
毫米
mmm
让我们修复它
let's fix it
转到计数器
go to counter
完美
perfect
不
no
我是否破坏了它
did i break it
如果计数器的值小于道具的最大值，就停止。
if the counter value is less than prop stop max
如此简单，却很容易被破坏
so simple it's so easy to break
当你能真正看到它时，它是如此的好
and it's so nice when you can actually just see it
从视觉上看是这样的。
visually there alright
所以从这里开始，让我们展示一些其他很酷的东西
so from there let's show off some other cool things
就像这个加号按钮，它被称为创建新规范
like this plus button here this is called create new spec
你可以从组件中创建
you can create from component
你会注意到，这些都是很好的视图文件，因为
and you'll notice that these are all nice view files because
因为该项目已经检测到了它的视图
the project has detected that it's view
但我要告诉你一些你可以做的奇怪的事情
but i'm going to show you some weird stuff you can do
所以你可以抓取其中的一个关于页面
so you can grab one of the about pages
所以
so
v tess会抓取markdown页面并为你渲染它们
v tess will grab markdown pages and it will render them for you
作为组件
as components
实际上会创建路由和其他东西
will actually create routes and stuff
所以这是一个真正能与视图组件一起工作的markdown组件。
so this is a markdown component that actually works
视图组件，这是我们的计数器
with view components here's our counter
这是我们之前的反驳，以证明
here is our counter from earlier to prove that
并证明它
and to prove that it
为了证明它是否有效，我将注释出
does it does or doesn't work i'm going to comment out
我们的增量和减量按钮里面的逻辑
the logic inside of our increment and decrement buttons
你会看到，关于页面
and you'll see that the about page
关于页面的重新加载变得很热
the about page gets hot reloading
这真是太酷了，让我们去看看关于MD吧
that is super cool let's go to about md
可以看到我们的约谈计数器
can see our about counter
我们可以开始在about size spec里面写测试。
and we can start to write tests inside of the about size spec
因为它是一个javascript文件
because it's a javascript file
它正在抱怨全局类型的问题
it's complaining about global types
我们可以开始编写测试，如获取数据测试ID
and we could start to write tests like get data test id
about counter
我们可以开始写测试，如get data test id about counter，并查看我们的东西是否被正确连接起来。
and see that our stuff is correctly hooked up i have
我从来没有见过一个应用程序或一个测试运行器，可以
never seen an application or a test runner that can
测试这样的markdown文件
test markdown files like this
v测试可能可以
v test probably can
毫无问题
with no problem
但我从来没有看到过能像这样显示的东西。
but i've never been able to see something that renders it like
这对我来说太酷了
this it's so cool to me
好了
alright
结束了
so wrapping up
我还有一些事情要在主题演讲中说
i have a few more things to say in the keynote
然后我们就可以了
and then we should be good
它们是关于
and they are concerning the
测试与塞浦路斯相比，只是
test versus cyprus versus just
我将跳过
i'm going to skip over
这一部分，因为基本上塞浦路斯
this section because basically cyprus
只是作为一个小麦的插件，让我移动我的小脸蛋
just acts as a wheat plug in let me move my little face
我们走吧
there we go
基本上Cyprus只是作为小麦的一个插件
basically cyprus just acts as a wheat plug in
进入点是一个动态的
and the entry point is ina dynamic is
一个加载器，它动态地导入每个规格文件
a loader that dynamically imports each spec file
所以它做了一个全球搜索，寻找
so it does a glob search for
匹配规范模式的东西
something that matches the spec pattern
cyprus使用dot cs
cyprus uses dot cs
以避免与
so as not to conflict with
v测试再次移动我的脸
v test moving my face again
与之相对应的是，我们给出了spec的扩展名
versus just so we are giving the extension of spec
和测试v测试
and test v test
因为你可能需要一个基于节点的运行器
because you probably need a node based runner
和一个基于浏览器的运行器
and a browser based runner
你可以使用V test的速度，它的速度快如闪电
you can use v test for its speed its lightning fast speed
而你可以使用Cyprus，因为它能够彻底测试
and you can use cyprus for its ability to test thoroughly
测试css
test css
所以我使用v test进行单元测试
so i use v test for unit tests
和业务逻辑以及无头组件
and business logic and headless composables
我使用Cyprus来测试渲染的组件
i use cyprus for components that render
我已经不再使用了
and i do not use just anymore
一些历史和感谢，我想更详细地讨论这个问题
some history and thanks i would go over this in more detail
但我已经没有时间了
but i'm out of time
我想说的是
all i would say is that
塞浦路斯从Vt的创造中得到了很大的启发
cyprus is highly inspired by the creation of vt
其目前的建筑
its current architecture
受到vt的强烈影响，如果没有vt的存在
is strongly influenced by vt and without vt's existence
很可能cyprus的组件测试
it is very likely that cyprus component testing
将会是非常网络化的
would have been very web
挤出来的
packed specific
为此，我非常感谢Evan所做的工作
and for that i am very thankful for the work that evan did
创建
to create
为此，我非常感谢伊万所做的工作，创建了维生素和维生素生态系统，所以感谢你
vit and the vit ecosystem so thank you